ach H. Pham

Faculty of Finance & Banking, HCMC Open University, Vietnam



💌 phamhoangthach@gmail.com | 🎢 thachpham.wordpress.com | 🖸 pham-hoang-thach | 🛅 phamhoangthach

2009-2010

2002

I like collaborative environments where I can learn from my peers. I have worked in a variety of roles ranging from financial and data analyst to investment officer to researcher and lecturer. I am passionate about education and I believe that none of subject is too complex if the teacher is empathetic and willing to think of new approaches. In my PhD thesis, I have developed a framework for stock selection strategies based on mispricing and smart betas. This framework not only helps in explaining stock returns but also in evaluating the efficiency of stock markets and trading strategies. I am using Linux and free and open-source softwares. I prefer literate programming, reproducible research, and plain text.

Education

Victoria University Melbourne, Australia

PhD, Asset Pricing 2018-2023

University of Wollongong NSW, Australia

University of Economics HCMC HCMC, Vietnam

BEC, PLANNING AND INVESTMENT 2002-2006

Training

MCOM, FINANCE

O'Reilly Online

PYTHON, SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING

Datastream, Refinitiv Eikon Melbourne, Australia 2018-2022

MACROECONOMIC INDICATORS AND FINANCIAL DATA TECHNOLOGY

Linkedin Learning Online R, TIDYVERSE 2018

EPICOR HCMC, Vietnam

ENTERPRISE RESOURCE PLANNING (ERP)

Thompson Reuters, Bloomberg HCMC, Vietnam

TRADING SYSTEMS OF STOCKS AND BONDS

IBM HCMC, Vietnam

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPER OF E-BUSINESS APPLICATIONS 2006-2008

Achievements

2023

2018–2020 Joint Victoria University and Vietnam International Education Development PhD Scholarship (VIED, 911)

Tuition and Stipend Sponsorship

Awarded for the

achievements

outstanding 2020 Top 15% highest achieving students, Victoria University academic

Tuition and Stipend 2021 Victoria University PhD Scholarship Sponsorship

Awarded for the outstanding **Excellent PhD Thesis** academic achievements.

Skills

- · Presentation, Research and Teaching
- Data Wrangling and Visualization
- Statistical and Financial Modeling
- Programming
- Version Control
- Linux and Open Source Software
- · Reporting and Writing
- Personal Knowledge Management and Personal Productivity



LATEX



Debian



Python



LaTeX zotero Zotero

Teaching

HCMC Open University

LECTURER

- Equity Analysis
- Fixed Income Analysis
- · Securities Analysis
- · Portfolio Management
- Financial Markets

Research Experience

Victoria University Melbourne, Australia

GRADUATE RESEARCHER

- Develop a framework for stock selection strategies based on mispricing and smart betas.
- Explain stock returns in both stock and portfolio levels
- Develop a new risk factor based on conditional Value-at-Risk
- · Measure market efficiency
- · Backtest trading strategies

University of Wollongong

GRADUATE RESEARCHER

• Financial Modeling & Valuation

- Portfolio Simulation & Asset Allocation
- Internal R&D Costs

Undergraduate Researcher

University of Economics HCMC

HCMC, Vietnam

NSW, Australia

HCMC, Vietnam

2012-Present

2018-2022

2005-2006

- · Conduct a research using cluster analysis to determine the main industries in Long An Province, Vietnam
- Operate a workshop of using multiple regression to determinate factors affecting gold prices in Vietnam
- Operate a workshop of linkage analysis (Input-Output Model)

Industry Experience _____

KPMG HCMC, Vietnam

Jun 2011–July 2012

Jul 2007-Sep 2008

2006

CONSULTANT OF STRATEGIC COMMERCIAL INTELLIGENCE (SCI)

- Market Research
- · Story Board
- Dashboard
- Visualisation
- Forecasting

ACB Securities (ACBS)

HCMC, Vietnam

FINANCIAL ANALYST & ADVISOR

- Stock Watch
- Financial Modeling
- Valuation
- · Writing Prospectus
- Public Offering & Private Placement Stocks & Bonds
- IPO & Auction Stocks
- · Listing Stocks on the Stock Exchanges

DongA Bank (DAB)

HCMC, Vietnam

DATA ANALYST (INTERNSHIP)

· Collecting and analysing data of using ATM cards and real estate

Publications

Pham, T.H. (2023). Stock Selection for Trading Strategies Based on Risk Factors: A Study of The Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange. [PhD Thesis, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia].

Dương Quỳnh Nga, Phạm Hò **Phạm Hoàng Thạch** (2022). *Quản lý danh mục đầu tư*. Tài liệu học tập. Đại học Mở Tp.HCM.

Pham, T.H., Wickremasinghe, G., Kulendran, N. (2022). *An empirical study of the cross-section of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange (HSX) in Vietnam.* Working Paper.

Pham, T.H., Wickremasinghe, G., Kulendran, N. (2022). *An empirical study of multifactor asset pricing models on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange (HSX) in Vietnam.* Working Paper.

Pham, T.H. (2019). A study of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange using ANOVA and multiple regressions. Working Paper.

Pham, T.H. (2018). *An empirical study of the cross-section of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange.* [Year 1 Thesis, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia].

Phạm Hoàng Thạch, Dương Quỳnh Nga (2018). *Quản lý danh mục đầu tư*. Slides bài giảng và video hướng dẫn môn học trực tuyến. Đại học Mở Tp.HCM.

Phạm Hoàng Thạch (2006). *Xác định các ngành công nghiệp chủ lực của tỉnh Long An* [Luận văn đại học, Đại học Kinh tế Tp.HCM, Tp.HCM, Việt Nam].